{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Ecuador","Bolivia","Colombia"],"question":"In which country is Machu Picchu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Azores","incorrectAnswers":["Madeira","Cape Verde","Canary Islands"],"question":"Which Portuguese island group includes Flores and Corvo as its northernmost islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Physician who made contributions to understanding how blood circulates in the body.","incorrectAnswers":["Physicist who made discoveries in atomic physics.","United most of Western Europe to form the Carolingian Empire.","Artist and photographer, who is credited with the invention of the camera."],"question":"Which of the following describes William Harvey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Squirrel","incorrectAnswers":["A Starfish","An Octopus","A Crab"],"question":"What kind of creature is Spongebob Squarepants' friend Sandy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bolivia","incorrectAnswers":["Trinidad and Tobago","Chile","Grenada"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Brazil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pisa ","incorrectAnswers":["Florence","Naples","Turin"],"question":"Which Italian City Is Famous For Its Leaning Tower","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Mercury","Venus","Jupiter"],"question":"Which planet is known as the red planet?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Verde","incorrectAnswers":["Groen","Grün","Seis"],"question":"What is the Spanish word for 'green'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["White","Green","Blue"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of North Macedonia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An ex-prize fighter struggles to stand up to his corrupt union bosses.","incorrectAnswers":["The life of a boxer whose temper led him to the top in the ring, but destroyed his life outside of it.","The story an English officer who successfully united and led the Arab tribes during World War I.","An Army officer serving in Vietnam is tasked with assassinating a renegade Special Forces Colonel."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie On the Waterfront?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Neigh","incorrectAnswers":["Moo","Baa","Oink"],"question":"What is the sound made by a horse when it 'whinnies'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["North America","China","Central America"],"question":"From which part of the world does cucumber originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"London","incorrectAnswers":["Cardiff","Edinburgh","Glasgow"],"question":"What is the capital of the United Kingdom","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Shark","incorrectAnswers":["Whale","Dolphin","Orca"],"question":"The fins of what sea creature are made into a soup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Répondez S'il Vous Plaît","incorrectAnswers":["Rester Sans Vôtre Poisson","Respond Soon Via Phone","Request Some Vacation Plans"],"question":"What does the 4-letter abbreviation RSVP stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter and the Three Champions","Harry Potter and the Triwizard Tournament","Harry Potter and the Tournament of Champions"],"question":"What is the title of the fourth book in the Harry Potter series?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Feedback","incorrectAnswers":["Echo","Resonance","Interference"],"question":"What word refers to distortion caused by a loop in a sound system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kidney","incorrectAnswers":["Liver","Spleen","Heart"],"question":"What is the name of the organ that filters blood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cool Hand Luke","incorrectAnswers":["The Silence of the Lambs","Untouchable","Jurassic Park"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A laid back man is sentenced to two years in a rural prison, but refuses to conform.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard II","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth I","Richard I","George V"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1377-1399?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"16","incorrectAnswers":["18","21","25"],"question":"What is the legal drinking age in Belgium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Robbins","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Roth","Hugo Weaving","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has featured in both The Shawshank Redemption and Mystic River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Brazil","Canada"],"question":"In one of Donald Horne's novels, which was \"the lucky country\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Brothers Karamazov'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ned Leeds","incorrectAnswers":["Loki","Ego","Groot"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Jacob Batalon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lady Godiva","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Gaga","Lady Geronimo","Lady Galebe"],"question":"Who is famous for historically riding naked on horseback through Coventry, England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Life of Brian","incorrectAnswers":["Terminator 2: Judgment Day","The Bridge on the River Kwai","Die Hard"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Born in the stable next door to Christ, a man spends his life being mistaken for a messiah.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hellraiser","incorrectAnswers":["Evil Dead","Saw","Halloween"],"question":"Which film first featured a character later named Pinhead?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Of which band is 'Roger Taylor' a member?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"100","incorrectAnswers":["0","273","71"],"question":"At What Temperature Centigrade Does Water Boil At?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sun Records","incorrectAnswers":["Capitol Records","Atlantic Records","Columbia Records"],"question":"Which record label from Memphis released five singles from Elvis Presley between July 1954 and August 1955?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ben Nevis","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Snowdon","Scafell Pike","Carrantouhill"],"question":"What is the highest mountain in the UK?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Duke","incorrectAnswers":["Harvard","Yale","Princeton"],"question":"What is the name of the university formerly known as Trinity College, which was named after a tobacco family that donated millions to the school?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Adams Family","incorrectAnswers":["The Von Trapps","The Flintstones","The Simpsons"],"question":"What Family Live At 1313 Cemetary Lane?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Tubular pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is bavette?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michael Crichton","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Jurassic Park'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band (1970-) released the song 'A Kind of Magic'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"El Cid","incorrectAnswers":["Don Quixote","Ferdinand II of Aragon","Zorro"],"question":"Which of these was an 11th-century  Spanish knight and warlord?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Zulu War","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam War","Spanish Civil War","Russian Civil War"],"question":"The Battle of Rorke's Drift in 1879 featured in which war?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iceland","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Croatia","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"In which country is the city of Reykjavik?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oliver Twist","incorrectAnswers":["Germinal","Eine Geschichte des Universums in 100 Sternen","Madame Bovary"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Among other public buildings in a certain town, which for many reasons it will be prudent to refrain from mentioning, and to which I will assign no fictitious name, there is one anciently common to most towns, great or small: to wit, a workhouse; and in this workhouse was born; on a day and date which I need not trouble myself to repeat, inasmuch as it can be of no possible consequence to the'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fauvism","incorrectAnswers":["Pointillism","Impressionism","Primitivism"],"question":"The painting \"The Dance\" by Henri Matisse is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Protagoras","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Socrates","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Man is the measure of all things'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John","incorrectAnswers":["George IV","Richard III","James I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1199-1216?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christopher Nolan","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Batman Begins?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Persian gulf","incorrectAnswers":["Suez Canal","Mediterranean Sea","The Nile"],"question":"What body of water borders Saudi Arabia to the east?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Grand National","incorrectAnswers":["The Africa Cup of Nations","The World Cup Sevens","The Copa América"],"question":"Which of these is a competition in Horse Racing?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Quidditch Through the Ages'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port Vila","incorrectAnswers":["São Tomé","Libreville","Naypyidaw"],"question":"What is the capital city of Vanuatu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Charles and Diana","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth and Philip","William and Kate","Harry and Megan"],"question":"Which British royal couple were married on the 29th July 1981?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Mare","incorrectAnswers":["A Hen","A Hembra","A Jill"],"question":"A female horse is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Holi","incorrectAnswers":["Diwali","Dusshera","Navaratri"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu festival of colors?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A crab","incorrectAnswers":["A lobster","A shrimp","A clam"],"question":"What animal is the symbol of the zodiac sign of Cancer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man sees the spotlight turned on him following his wife's disappearance.","incorrectAnswers":["A woman works with a hardened boxing trainer to become a professional.","A boy and his little sister struggle to survive in Japan during World War II.","A kindhearted street urchin and a power-hungry Grand Vizier vie for a magic lamp."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Gone Girl?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Iraq","Korea","Afghanistan"],"question":"Battles known as Con Thien and Hamburger Hill were fought during which 20th century conflict?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Strand pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Shaped pasta","Tubular pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is vermicelli?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"All the King's Men","incorrectAnswers":["Gone With the Wind","Lonesome Dove","Love in the Time of Cholera"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Willie Stark'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Edward","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur","William","Henry"],"question":"What is the first name of the composer Elgar, who wrote the famous piece known as 'Pomp and Circumstance'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Sweet Jane","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Suede Shoes","I Love Rock 'n' Roll","Tainted Love"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by The Velvet Underground and was later covered by Cowboy Junkies?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Nietzsche","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Spinoza","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Is man merely a mistake of God's? Or God merely a mistake of man's?'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Manama","incorrectAnswers":["Palikir","Moroni","Muscat"],"question":"What is the capital city of Bahrain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Togo","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Mali","Cambodia"],"question":"Lomé is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Caledonia","incorrectAnswers":["Newfoundland","Vanuatu","Huron"],"question":"What did the Romans call Scotland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"President Nassar","incorrectAnswers":["President Kassar","President Passar","President Hassar"],"question":"Which Egyptian president ordered the seizure of the Suez Canal in 1956?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Turkic","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'Algerian Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kingstown","incorrectAnswers":["Yamoussoukro","Manama","Banjul"],"question":"What is the capital city of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Bulgaria","Israel"],"question":"In which country would you find Schönbrunn Palace and Gardens?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cranberry juice","incorrectAnswers":["Pomegranate juice","Cherry juice","Raspberry juice"],"question":"What juice makes a Cape Cod cocktail red?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","Belgium","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the Yellowstone National Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the studio album 'The Fame Monster'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"'Liberian Girl' is a song by which musician?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Nicolaus Copernicus","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galilei","Ptolemy","Isaac Newton"],"question":"Who coined the theory that the earth revolves around the sun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henryk Sienkiewicz","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Ivan Turgenev","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Quo Vadis'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The causes and treatment of allergies","incorrectAnswers":["Wine","Fossils of ancient life","Interactions between organisms and geomorphological processes"],"question":"What is Allergology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honda","incorrectAnswers":["Ford","Citroën","Chevrolet"],"question":"The Accord is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Millard Fillmore","incorrectAnswers":["Zachary Taylor","William H. Taft","John F. Kennedy"],"question":"Who was the 13th president of the USA, in term during the period 1850–1853?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Melons","incorrectAnswers":["Oranges","Apples","Bananas"],"question":"What is the common name for the fruits named casaba, crenshaw, and honeydew?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stapes","incorrectAnswers":["Femur","Humerus","Tibia"],"question":"What is the smallest bone in the human body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Banana","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Lemon","Grapefruit"],"question":"Which of these fruits is not a citrus fruit?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Twelfth Night","incorrectAnswers":["A Midsummer Night's Dream","The Winter's Tale","Coriolanus"],"question":"What Shakespearean play refers to the date of epiphany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kyrgyzstan","incorrectAnswers":["Belarus","Tajikistan","Azerbaijan"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Bishkek?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Panama","Mexico","Ecuador"],"question":"Where would you find the city of São Paulo?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice","incorrectAnswers":["Bread","Apples","Potatoes"],"question":"What type of food has varieties such as Jasmine, Arborio, and Texmati?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grain","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Wine","Butter"],"question":"What type of food is barley?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","San Marino","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which country borders Italy, Switzerland, Germany, Czech Republic, Hungary, Slovenia, and Liechtenstein?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the studio album 'Dangerously in Love'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Northern Crown","incorrectAnswers":["Great Light","Brave Hunter","Dazzling Forest"],"question":"What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Corona Borealis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kathy Bates","incorrectAnswers":["Maggie Smith","Helen Mirren","Kate Winslet"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in both American Horror Story and Titanic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tbilisi","incorrectAnswers":["Beirut","Bratislava","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Georgia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Laos","Vietnam"],"question":"____________ means \"land of the free.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Brass","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Stringed","Percussion"],"question":"What type of instrument is a didgeridoo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["England","Spain","Germany"],"question":"Which country was the main power in Europe during the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the studio album 'Ghost Stories'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I don't care","incorrectAnswers":["I didn't cry","I desire cash","If darling comes"],"question":"What do people mean when type the letters 'IDC' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nero","incorrectAnswers":["Noir","Zwart","Nove"],"question":"What is the Italian word for 'black'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Yellow","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Luxembourg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ghost in the Machine","incorrectAnswers":["Synchronicity","Reggatta de Blanc","Outlandos d'Amour"],"question":"What is the name of the 1981 album by The Police that was named after a 1967 book by Arthur Koestler?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Sholokhov","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'And Quiet Flows the Don'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colorado and Wyoming","incorrectAnswers":["Texas and Illinois","Florida and Georgia","Maine and Nevada"],"question":"What two US states are rectangular?","difficulty":"medium"},